Fire!
着火了
- Fire! - Fire! Fire!
着火了 着火了
- Fire! Hurry. - Go put out the fire!
快快快 着火了 快
Go put out the fire!
快去救火啊
Be quick.
快
The West Hall is on fire!
西堂着火了
- Hurry, hurry.
快快快
Hurry.
快快
Put out the fire.
快救火
Hurry, hurry.
快快快
- Here's the water. - Put out the fire!
水来了
Hurry.
快
Ma'am.
太太 哪里啊
- The West Hall is on fire. - Go put out the fire. Hurry.
是西堂着了火
It's on fire for a while.
烧了一阵了
Where's Master? Have you got him out?
老爷呢 救出来没有啊
Don't worry, Ma'am.
太太别着急
Master is out.
老爷救出来了
We've sent him to the main house.
我们已经送到主楼里了
I'm relieved, then.
那就好
- Go get Mr. Jiashang back. - What are you waiting for? Put out the fire.
赶紧去把大少爷给叫回来
- Go, go. - Yes.
快去
- Come on. - Be quick. Be quick.
快快快 快点
Water. Hurry.
水 快
Here's the water. Here it is.
水来了 水来了
Hurry. Hurry.
快点 快
Here's the water.
来了
Put out the fire!
赶紧救火
Hello.
喂
It's me.
是我
Would you like to make a deal with me?
想不想和我做笔交易啊
Don't worry.
你放心
After you make it,
把事办成
you will get
你想要的
whatever you want.
我都会满足你
Don't let me down.
不要让我失望
Jiashang.
哥
Why was the West Hall on fire?
西堂怎么会着火呢
I don't know.
不知道
The fire wasn't big and it was put out quickly.
火势不大 很快就灭了
What about Father?
爹呢
He was got out. He's in the main house.
救出来了 在里面呢
Who were you calling, Father?
爹在给谁打电话呢
The Fire Station.
消防局呀
Somebody.
来人
Clean up my father's room.
在
Take him back for some rest.
带老爷回去歇息
Without my permission,
没有我的允许
he mustn't leave the second floor.
不准老爷离开二楼
- Yes.
是
Father,
爹
please stay at home obediently
请你安安生生的待在家里
and play no more tricks.
别再耍什么花样了
Son,
儿子
you don't understand
你根本不理解
what a man can do
一个人为了保护他自己的家
to protect his family.
会做到什么地步
Whoever wants to ruin my family,
凡是要毁了我容家的人
I will destroy him, too.
我也一定要毁了他
What do you want to do again?
你又想做什么
Keep an eye on him.
看着老爷
- Yes.
是
Hello.
你好
Is the dress that I booked the day before yesterday ready?
我前天订的衣服好了吗
Miss Feng, my boss wants to see you.
冯小姐 我们家主子想见见你
Come with us.
跟我们走一趟吧
Go.
走
Newspapers.
卖报瞧报了
Revolutionaries will be wiped out.
政府今起肃清革命党
Who covers them will be executed, too.
有包庇者同罪论处
- Wen. - Newspapers.
卖报瞧报了
Thank you.
谢谢
- Why is the government checking - Revolutionaries will be wiped out.
你说这怎么又查起进步人员了
What a mess!
这一天天的
Don't ask when we're not involved.
不关我们的事别瞎问
- Or Mr. Meng will criticize you. - Newspapers.
小心七爷说你
The... the bag...
这 这包是
Whose bag is it?
什么情况
It's Miss Feng's bag.
这是冯小姐的包
She forgot to take it when she got off, I guess.
肯定刚才停车的时候忘了拿了
Here. Hold it for me.
来 你帮我拿着
Wait here for me. I'll go give it to her.
在这儿等我啊
All right.
好
Miss Feng.
冯小姐
Where's the lady who came to fetch her dress?
刚才取衣服那小姐呢
She was kidnapped.
被人绑了
They ran that way.
往那边去了
Oh, no!
糟了
Sir,
大哥
may I open the window?
我 我能开会儿窗户吗
I feel too dizzy.
头晕得难受
Let her do it.
随她吧
She can't run away from the car, anyway.
反正在车上她又跑不了
Don't make her scared to death before we arrive.
别没到地方先把她吓死了
Thank you.
谢谢
Sorry. Sorry to have hit you.
不好意思 不好意思 把您撞了
Are you all right?
您没事吧
Yes.
没事
Where did you get it?
哪儿来的
I picked it up.
这是我捡的
Where did you pick it up?
哪儿捡的
Over there.
就在那里
Take me there.
带我去看看
Where?
在哪儿啊
Over there.
就是那里捡的
There.
就那里
Here?
这儿是吧
Thank you, then.
谢谢你
What did you say?
你说什么
Say it again!
你再说一遍
Miss Feng...
冯小姐她
She was kidnapped.
她被人劫走了
Wen is catching up.
文哥已经追上去了
He asked me to come back and tell you.
他让我来告诉您
Where was the car going?
车往哪儿开了
To the south of the city out of the tailor shop.
向着裁缝铺往城南的方向
I don't know
接着再去哪儿
where it was going later.
我就不知道了
Take all our men and search the south of the city
带上所有人分成几队
in teams.
往南边找
Search from door to door.
挨家挨户的搜
If you find anything,
有任何消息
let me know.
随时通知我
All right.
好
In broad daylight,
光天化日之下
who dared to kidnap her?
谁有这么大的胆子
Who else can it be?
还能有谁啊
If Shizhen is hurt,
世真要是有任何闪失
I'll cut him into pieces!
我一定将他碎尸万段
It's you?
是你
Sorry, Miss Feng.
冯小姐 对不住了
But if I didn't kidnap you,
要是不这样
I wouldn't have got you here.
怎么请得动你呢
Miss Hashimoto, why did you take the trouble
桥本小姐这么大动干戈
to have kidnapped me
把我绑到这儿来
to this place?
是想做什么
To kill you.
杀了你
I don't think you hate me a lot.
我不觉得跟你有深仇大恨
Why do you want to kill me?
为什么要杀我
You're wrong.
错
I hate you.
我恨你
You're quite self-righteous.
你这个自以为是的女人
You pretend to be aloof and proud.
表面装得多清高孤傲
But you're just a poor governess who's good at stealing.
不过是个惯会偷人的穷先生罢了
Do you know how you'll end up for stealing my man?
知道和我抢男人的下场吗
Stealing your man?
抢男人
That's not the right way to put it.
这个词用得不太恰当吧
Rong Jiashang and I
我跟容嘉上
attracted each other.
是互相吸引
How shameless!
不要脸
You finally admit that you seduced Jiashang?
你终于承认你勾引阿上了
We like each other.
我们是惺惺相惜
Why would I deny it?
有什么好否认的
Wrong!
错
He loves me.
他爱的是我
You don't know anything.
你什么都不知道
You don't know what happened between us.
你不知道我们之前发生过什么
When we were in Chongqing,
我们之前在重庆的时候
Jiashang said
阿上说
I was the camellia in the mountain.
我是山间的茶花
He listened when I played the piano.
他会听我弹琴
He walked me home.
会送我回家
He even fought others for me.
还会为了我跟别人打架
But after I met him again,
但重逢之后
everything changed.
一切都变了
I've been so nice to him.
我对他那么好
But he totally ignores me.
他却视而不见
Now, I have a sweetheart.
我现在已经有心上人了
A man must move on
人要往前走
and look forward.
目光要向前看
You should also drag yourself out of the past.
你也该从那段经历走出来了
It's all because of you!
这一切都是因为你
Without you,
要不是因为你
Jiashang and I would have got back together!
我早就和阿上重修旧好了
Are you so sure
你就那么坚信
that after you kill me,
杀了我
Rong Jiashang will love you?
容嘉上就会爱上你吗
Don't you know?
你还不知道吗
Men are all the same.
男人都是一样的
A man wants a woman who he can't have.
得不到的才是最好的
After he has her,
得到了
he'll no longer cherish her.
也就不珍惜了
I still have some confusion.
我还真有些想不明白
Miss Hashimoto, you're from such a good family
桥本小姐的家世这么好
and you can pick from many men.
一大把男人任你选
Why must you be obsessed with Rong Jiashang?
为何非得盯着一个容嘉上
Those men are different.
那些人能一样吗
How can such playboys be as good as Jiashang?
那些纨绔子弟怎么跟阿上比
Besides,
况且
he's the only heir of the Rong family.
阿上还是容家唯一的继承人
Rong Dingkun promised me.
容定坤答应过我
After you die,
只要你死了
I'll be Jiashang's wife.
我以后就是容家的大少奶奶
What are you laughing at?
你笑什么
I thought you were a clever woman.
我还以为桥本小姐是个聪明人呢
But you turned out to be so naive.
原来这么天真
When used as Rong Dingkun's chess piece,
你都被容定坤当成棋子了
you didn't realize it at all.
还浑然不知
How pathetic you are!
真是可怜
Think about it.
你也不想一想
Before Rong Dingkun was disabled,
容定坤在健全的时候
Rong Jiashang never took his orders.
容嘉上对他的指令就不屑一顾
Now, will he be ordered about
那现在容嘉上还会听一个
by a disabled old man?
瘫痪老头子的摆布吗
In fact,
其实
you never love Rong Jiashang
你爱的从来就不是容嘉上
but his identity and property.
只是他的身份和财产
You're such a selfish woman.
像你这么自私的女人
Jiashang will never love you.
嘉上永远都不可能爱上你的
Shut up!
你住口
What do you think you are?
你算什么东西
How dare you
就凭你
judge me!
也敢评判我
Look at your beautiful face.
瞧这张勾人的脸
If it's scratched,
要是划花了
will Jiashang still be crazy about it?
阿上还会不会着迷呢
Qin Shuigen!
秦水根
- Mr. Meng. - Come out!
孟老板
There's no Qin Shuigen here, Mr. Meng.
我们没有这个人 孟老板
No one in our residence is named Qin.
我们容府上下就没有一个姓秦的
Mr. Meng,
不知道孟老板
what are you coming for?
来我们容家做什么
Mr. Jiashang.
少爷
Why do you have the nerve to ask me?
还有脸问我做什么
Your father had Shizhen kidnapped.
你爹绑架了世真
I want you to give her back to me.
我希望你把人交出来
Nonsense!
你在胡说什么
Shizhen was kidnapped.
世真被人绑架了
Who else would do that,
除了你爹
except your father?
还有谁会这么做
No way.
不可能
He's been watched over.
我一直派人看着他呢
Mr. Jiashang,
那就请容少爷
go ask your father, then.
去问问令尊吧
Meng Xu'an.
孟绪安
What a rare visitor!
稀客
Where is Feng Shizhen?
冯世真在哪儿
Why must I tell you?
我为什么要告诉你
Believe it or not, I'll shoot you!
你信不信老子崩了你
If you kill me,
打死我
you can never see her again.
你们永远都别再想见到她
Father,
爹
you indeed had her kidnapped?
真的是你做的
Where's Shizhen?
世真到底在哪里
If she's hurt,
她要是有什么事的话
I'll cut you into pieces!
我让你死无全尸
Jiashang,
嘉上啊
will you just watch it
你就这么看着他用枪
when he points at your father with a gun?
顶着你父亲的头吗
Meng Xu'an.
孟绪安
Father,
爹
please tell me
请你告诉我
where Shizhen is.
世真到底在哪里
As long as you tell us,
只要你说出来
you won't be hurt.
就没有人会伤害你
I'll even return the power to you
哪怕是容家的大权
without reserve.
我也会全数还给你
Good son.
好孩子
However,
不过
it's too late.
来不及了
You'll never see her again.
你们永远都别再想见到她了
What did you say?
你说什么
What on earth did you do?
你到底做了什么
Mr. Meng,
七爷
we've found Wen's car.
找到阿文的车了
You'd better pray that Shizhen is all right.
你最好祈祷世真没事
Let's go.
跟我走
What a sunny day!
阳光真好
Don't worry.
你放心
I won't kill you so easily.
我不会就这么轻易杀掉你的
I'll scratch your face
我要一刀
stroke by stroke
一刀的划花你的脸
and make you witness the process.
让你看到自己容貌尽毁
I'll see how you can still seduce Jiashang.
到时候还怎么勾引阿上
How dare you kick me!
你竟然敢踢我
You cheap woman!
你这个贱人
Die, you cheap woman!
你去死吧你这个贱人
Miss Feng, are you all right?
冯小姐你没事吧
Wen.
阿文
Wen, watch out!
阿文 小心
Miss Feng, be careful!
冯小姐小心
Are you all right?
你没事吧
Wen.
阿文
Wen. Wen.
阿文 阿文
Zhen?
桢
Li?
小立
He's my younger brother.
他是我弟弟
How come?
他怎么会是我弟弟
How can you be my brother?
你怎么会是我弟弟呢
Li.
小立
Get him up. Get him to the hospital.
快扶起来 先去医院
Save him first.
救人要紧
- Somebody.
来人啊
Get him to the hospital. Hurry!
送医院 送医院 快
Yes.
是
- Li! - Go.
小立
Hurry.
快 快
- Go. - Hurry.
走
Save him.
快救他
Doctor! Doctor!
医生 医生
Doctor!
医生
Doctor, hurry!
医生 快点
The operation was successful.
手术很成功
He's no longer in danger.
已经脱离生命危险了
However,
不过
his brain was starved of oxygen from excessive blood loss.
因为失血过多造成脑缺氧
He's now in a coma.
现在处于昏迷中
When he can wake up
什么时候能醒
depends on his luck.
那就要看他自己的造化了
Would you like
要不要
to have some rest?
去休息一下
I'll ask someone to take care of him.
我派人盯着
The 27th year of Emperor Guangxu.
光绪二十七年
July 24.
七月二十四日
Half past one
未时
in the afternoon.
三刻
It's my birth date.
这是我的生辰
This is my longevity lock.
这是我的长命锁
Li,
小立
you turn out to be around all the time,
原来你一直就在我的身边
protecting me.
一直守护着我
You will wake up.
你一定会醒过来的
I'll accompany you.
姐姐陪着你
It was negligent of me.
是我疏忽了
I should have come earlier.
我应该早些过来
Mr. Meng,
七爷
how's Li been doing
小立他这些年
in recent years?
过得怎么样
I remember
我记得
when I first met him,
第一次见他的时候
he was roaming about
在街上
on the street.
他在流浪
I thought he was a poor boy.
我看这孩子挺可怜的
I gave him some money and talked with him.
就给他一些钱
He was very clever
他很机灵的
and he was a quick learner.
学什么都很快
I liked him.
我很喜欢
So, I've kept him working for me.
所以就把他留在身边了
I wish I were lying in bed.
我多希望现在躺在这儿的是我
He's so young.
他还这么年轻
Listen.
那个
According to the doctor,
刚才医生说过了
he's still in a coma.
虽然他在昏迷
However,
但是
he isn't in danger.
没有生命危险的
Don't worry.
你放心
I promise that he'll wake up.
我保证他一定会醒过来的
Just now,
刚才
I was too busy to ask you.
急着救人没来得及问
Shizhen,
世真
what happened? Why is Wen...?
到底发生什么事
It's my fault.
还是怪我呀
It's some business conflict.
生意上的一些事情
You know.
你知道
People like us
道上的人吧
often have conflicts.
难免会有些冲突
Shizhen,
世真
come out with me.
跟我出来一下
All right.
好
Shizhen,
世真
I know.
我知道
Mr. Meng helped you a lot.
孟七爷帮了你很多
But he's a gangster, after all.
但他毕竟是道上的人
He's way too dangerous.
太危险了
You'd better have less contact with him
以后还是少接触
in case we worry about you.
免得家里人担心
Shixun,
哥
you know what?
你知道吗
Wen is
阿文
my younger brother I've been looking for.
就是我一直找的亲弟弟
Brother?
弟弟
His real name is Li.
他叫小立
We lost each other for years.
是我失散多年的弟弟
I've been looking for him.
我一直在找他
I've finally found him.
终于找到他了
Shizhen, don't cry.
世真别哭
It's all right. Don't cry.
没事 别哭
Don't be sad.
别伤心
He'll be all right.
小立一定会好起来的
Everything will be all right.
这一切都会好起来的
Stop crying.
别哭了
Do you have any feelings?
有感觉吗
Mr. Hashimoto.
桥本先生
Yes, please.
您说
Your daughter's leg was wounded
令爱的腿伤了筋脉
without timely treatment.
又没有及时救治
I'm afraid
怕是
she can hardly recover
很难痊愈
and she'll have a permanent disability.
会落下终生残疾啊
How come?
怎么可能
I was just shot.
我就受了这点伤
Why would I be disabled?
怎么可能会残疾呢
You useless doctor!
你这个庸医
Get out!
出去
But...
诗织
Fine.
好
Sorry.
对不起
Please leave.
请
This way, please.
这边请
Fine.
好
Mr. Hashimoto, don't bother to walk me out.
桥本先生请留步
Father, get me to another hospital.
父亲 我要换医院
I'm leaving today.
我今天马上就要走
How do you have the nerve to lose your temper?
你还有脸发脾气
You brought such trouble
弄成今天这个样子
to yourself.
都是你咎由自取
You've disgraced our family!
桥本家的脸都让你丢尽了
You look obedient.
平时看着文文静静的
But you did such a terrible thing.
竟然做出这样的事情
We don't know
真不知道
what else you did behind us.
还背着我们做过什么
Father.
父亲
Father, help me.
父亲你帮帮我吧
I'll be obedient.
我以后一定好好听话
I won't make trouble anymore.
我再不乱来了
I'm still young. I don't want to be lame.
我还年轻 我不想瘸
Shut up!
你给我住嘴
Don't you feel humiliated enough?
还嫌不够丢人吗
Mr. Rong.
容少爷
Mr. Hashimoto.
桥本先生
Mrs. Hashimoto.
桥本太太
I came to see Shiori.
我是来看诗织的
Thank you, Mr. Rong.
容少爷你有心了
But I'm afraid
只怕
Shiori is emotionally unstable now.
诗织现在情绪不稳定
It doesn't matter.
不碍事的
Could you give us a second?
我想单独和她说几句
Jiashang, there you are.
阿上 你来了
What would you like to say?
你要跟我说什么
I was forced
冯小姐的事
to kidnap Miss Feng.
我是被逼的
Your father forced me to kill her.
你父亲逼我杀了她
I didn't want that.
我也不想的
Shiori,
诗织
you shouldn't have hurt her.
你不该动她的
I know.
我知道
But I can't stand it
可是我受不了
when she stole all your attention.
她抢走你所有的注意力
You were supposed to focus on me.
那些本来都应该是属于我的
I want her dead. I want her to drop dead!
她该死 她该死
As long as she dies
只要她死了
and disappears,
她消失了
you'll love me again.
你就会重新爱上我的
When we met last time,
上次见面的时候
I explained it to you very clearly.
我已经和你说得很清楚了
Even without Shizhen,
就算没有世真
I wouldn't love you
我也不会爱你
or marry you.
更不会娶你
Why?
为什么
You used to love me in Chongqing, didn't you?
你之前在重庆不是很爱我吗
That day,
那天
I heard your conversation
你和你母亲的话
with your mother.
我都听到了
Mother,
妈妈
Jiashang came to listen to me play the piano again today.
今天阿上又来听我弹琴了
He likes me, I guess.
我觉得他可能喜欢我
Do you like him, then?
那你喜欢他吗
I don't know.
我也不知道
But we won't be together.
但我们俩是不可能在一起的
Why?
为什么
He's a handsome man, isn't he?
他模样不是挺英俊的吗
He is handsome.
长得是挺好看的
But I hear
可是我听别人说
he's from a poor family.
他家条件不好
I'm on good terms with him,
我现在与他交好
simply to play him.
不过是吊着他而已
Anyway,
不管怎么说
I'm Mr. Hashimoto's daughter.
我也是桥本家的小姐
If one day Father thinks of us
如果有一天父亲想起我们来了
and gets us back,
把我们接回去
he won't be
那到时候
good enough for me then.
他自然是配不上我的
Jiashang...
阿上
I was standing by the door that day.
那天我就站在门口
I didn't give you the flowers that day.
那日没有送出去的花
I won't give them to you again.
以后我永远都不会再送了
Jiashang.
阿上
Jiashang, I'm sorry.
阿上 我错了
Jiashang, forgive me.
阿上 阿上你原谅我
Jiashang. Jiashang.
阿上 阿上
I'm sorry.
我错了
Jiashang, forgive me.
阿上你原谅我
Forgive me, please.
你原谅我
I... I didn't understand.
是我 是我不懂
I didn't understand love.
我不懂爱
I was too childish!
我当时太天真了
Forgive me, Jiashang!
你原谅我阿上
Everyone has to pay for what he does.
人要为自己做的事情付出代价
Hope you'll wise up.
你好自为之吧
Jiashang, Jiashang!
阿上 阿上
Jiashang!
阿上
How's Shiori?
诗织怎么样了
I picked this up
这是我那日
at the auction.
在拍卖会现场捡到的
I'm giving it back to you.
今日物归原主
See you.
告辞
Don't worry, Ma'am.
太太放心
I've brought his medicine.
哥哥的药带了
Take a breath. Hurry.
喘口气 快
Taichi, take the medicine.
大哥 吃药
Taichi, don't panic.
太一 别慌啊
Father.
父亲
Father, I don't want to get married.
父亲我不想嫁人 父亲
Father, save me. Father.
父亲你救救我吧父亲
Father.
父亲
I don't want to marry Matsuda, Father.
我不想嫁给松田 父亲
I beg you!
女儿求求你了
- Father. - Shiori.
父亲
Your marriage has been decided.
此事已经决定了
Say no more about it!
不用再说了
Shiori.
姐
Say no more, Shiori.
别说了姐
Go. Say no more.
走吧 别说了
Don't annoy Father.
别惹怒父亲
Go, Shiori.
走吧姐
I beg you.
我求求你了
I don't want to marry Matsuda, Father.
我不想嫁给松田 父亲
Mr. Matsuda agrees to marry you
松田先生是看在你父亲的面子上
for your father's sake.
才娶你进门的
Shiori,
诗织
what you should do now is
你现在唯一要做的就是
to marry Mr. Matsuda
好好地嫁入松田家
and take good care of him,
好好服侍松田先生
helping with your father's relationship with the Japanese military.
替你父亲维系好与日本军方的关系
Learn to be content.
要学会知足
No.
不
I don't want to marry him.
我不要嫁给他
Father,
父亲
I hear Colonel Matsuda
我听说那个松田大佐
can be very ruthless.
生性暴戾
His wives...
他前几任
His former wives
他前几任太太
died after being abused by him.
都是被他虐待致死的
Father.
父亲
Nonsense!
一派胡言
He's from a notable family. He won't abuse you!
人家是名门望族 岂会亏待你
Father.
父亲
Father! Father!
父亲 父亲
Mother.
母亲
I beg you.
我求你
Help me. Help me.
你救救我
I don't want to die.
我不想死
Mother.
母亲
Tell me...
你以后
Tell me to do anything.
你以后让我做什么都可以
I'll be your slave.
我给你做牛做马
I can do anything for you.
我什么都可以做
Have pity on me.
可怜可怜我
Have pity on you?
我可怜你
Do you really think you can deceive everyone?
你真觉得自己可以瞒天过海吗
You killed my son.
你害死了我的太一
Do you think I'll make you live a good life?
你觉得我会让你好过吗
Mother, what are you talking about?
母亲 你在说什么呀
I'll watch you
我就是要看着你
be tortured forever.
生不如死
Marry Matsuda and enjoy the good life.
你就好好地嫁入松田家享福吧
Mr. Matsuda promised me.
松田先生已经答应我了
He said
他说
he would be nice to you
他会厚待你的
and you wouldn't die easily.
绝不会那么容易让你死
Take your sister away
把你姐姐带下去
and keep an eye on her.
给我看好了
Don't let her run away
不能让她逃
or kill herself.
更不能让她死
Before she marries Matsuda,
在她嫁入松田家之前
if anything happens,
如果出什么意外的话
I'll make you wish you were never born.
我会让你更加生不如死
Do you hear me?
听见了吗
Out!
出去
Shiori, let's go.
姐 走吧
Let's go, Shiori.
走吧 姐
Somebody.
来人
Shiori.
姐
Nowadays,
当今
big powers collude
列强勾结
to invade our nation and kill our countrymen.
侵我主权 戮我同胞
Warlords keep fighting wars.
军阀混战
The government is incompetent.
政府无所作为
- Yeah. - That's right.
是啊
- Yes. - Mm.
是
The assembly will be in three days.
三日后的集会
You shall all get ready.
大家都做好准备
- We will.
好 好
Shixun and I
我跟世勋
will come from the south
带着纺织厂的工人们
with the workers from the textile mill.
从南面走
You shall come from the north
你们带着学生
with the students.
从北边过来
All right.
好
Let's meet at No. 16 Terminal.
咱们
Deal.
好
Nobody moves!
都别动
What...
这
Be right there.
来了来了
Ms. Zhong?
钟阿姨
Mrs. Feng,
冯太太
- your son was caught. - Ah?
你儿子被抓起来了
When I passed the newspaper office,
我怕今天路过报馆的时候呀
I saw the police catch a group of young men.
看见警察抓了一大批小青年
Your son was among them.
其中就有你们家世勋
Go check it out in the police station.
你快去警察局看看吧
What happened?
怎么了
Shixun was caught.
世勋被抓起来了
Our son?
我们家世勋
Speak slowly.
您慢点说
Don't be anxious, Mother.
妈 别急
Aunt Zhong, did you see it clearly?
钟阿姨 你看清楚了吗
Was that really my brother?
是我哥吗
Yes, yes. I saw it clearly. That was him.
是的是的 看清楚了 没错
I took a closer look at him.
我还特地上前多看了两眼
It's the newspaper office
是那个小桥头
at the bridgehead.
那个什么报馆
What's its name?
叫什么名字来着
I can't think of it at the moment.
我一下子想不起来了
Father, don't be anxious.
爹 您别着急
I'll go check it out.
我赶紧去看看啊
Ms. Zhong, did you see it clearly?
钟阿姨你看清楚 是他吗
Yes, yes. That was him.
看清楚了 没错
No way!
不可能啊
Shixun has no friends in a newspaper office.
我们家世勋他没报社的朋友啊
Yeah.
是啊
What on earth happened?
这到底是怎么回事
Father, don't worry.
爹 别着急
Mother, I'll go check on him.
妈 我马上去看一下
Wait until I come back.
回来跟你们说啊
- Wait for me. - All right.
你们等着
Go check it out.
你快去认一下
Shizhen.
世真
You should be careful, too.
你也当心点
Shizhen!
世真
Our family must be sticking together!
我们一家人一定要整整齐齐的
Hello.
喂
Mr. Jiashang, it's me.
大少爷 是我
What's up?
怎么了
The man spying on Miss Feng reported
暗中保护冯小姐的人回报
that her brother was caught
冯小姐的哥哥
as a revolutionary.
被当成革命党给抓起来了
Excuse me.
你好
Register before you report a case.
报案先去那边登记一下
I don't report a case.
我不报案
I came to see someone.
我找人
See someone?
找人哪
Right.
对
Who?
找谁呀
A man, named Feng Shixun.
姓冯 叫冯世勋
He's a doctor at Red House Hospital.
是红房子医院的医生
He's among the guys you caught this evening.
你们今天傍晚抓的人里面有他
He's my elder brother. I'm his sister.
是我大哥 我是他妹妹
I want to see him.
我想见见他
Who are you?
你谁呀
You think you own the police station
你当警察局是你家开的
and you can see anyone you want?
你想见谁就见谁啊
Could you do me a favor?
您能帮帮忙吗
They are no longer here.
这些人早就不在这儿了
Do you know where they are?
您知道他们去哪儿了吗
They were sent to Tilanqiao Prison.
都被送去提篮桥那边了
As their case is confidential,
这批犯人事关机密
the superiors will interrogate them personally.
上面人说要亲自审问
Please do me a favor.
帮帮忙
I want to see him.
我想见见他
Miss,
小姐
I can't help you.
这我可帮不了你啊
This is all that I know.
我知道的就这么多
They're insurgents.
抓的都是动乱分子
If anything goes wrong,
出了问题
they'll die.
是要命的
My brother is a mere doctor.
我大哥只是个医生
He can't be the one you want.
绝对不可能是你们要抓的人
We don't care.
谁管你是不是啊
Now that he's in prison,
抓进去了
he'll be charged at whatever cost.
没什么也得查出点什么呢
I'm afraid
你大哥呀
your brother can hardly survive.
怕是凶多吉少了
Tilanqiao Prison?
提篮桥监狱
Who's that?
谁啊
Baoli.
宝丽
Shizhen?
世真
What happened?
怎么了
Why did you come in the middle of the night?
这么晚出什么事了
Baoli,
宝丽
please help me.
你一定得帮帮我
What happened?
怎么了
Listen.
你听我讲
My brother was caught by the police as an insurgent.
我哥被警察当成进步人士关起来了
I've got to know
我刚才打听到
that they're locked in Tilanqiao Prison.
他们现在全部都被关在提篮桥监狱
Can you find a way
你有没有门路
to let me see him?
安排我进去见见我哥
Insurgent?
进步人士
Has your brother mentioned it to you?
那你哥之前有跟你提过吗
You know.
你知道的
My brother keeps a low profile and works hard.
我哥他又低调又踏实
He only works at the hospital or stays at home.
每天除了医院就是回家
He never makes trouble.
他从来不惹事的
It's my fault.
都怪我不好
that I didn't care about my brother.
都没有去关心我哥
Take it easy.
你先别着急
I've heard about hunting insurgents.
搜捕进步人士 我有耳闻
It was a sudden decision.
那局势也是突然变动的
It's not your fault.
怪不得你
But I do have friends at the police station.
不过 我还真有认识警察局的朋友
I'll go ask about it for you.
我去帮你打听打听
Sure. I'll count on you.
好 那就拜托你了
Don't be anxious.
别着急
Go back home and accompany your parents.
你先回去好好陪着伯父伯母
Wait until I call you.
等我消息
Thank you, Baoli.
谢谢宝丽